Hi.
I'm Michael Burton and we're talking about choosing a wedding videographer for your wedding day.
One important thing that you should do with your wedding videographer when you're booking your wedding is to make sure that you guys sign a contract together.
That's important for both sides because you need to know exactly what is expected of each other.
The videographer needs to know that you're not going to back out and that you're not going to change your wedding day.
And you need to know that your videographer is going to be there or your wedding day, especially if you don't talk to him for another month or two or a few weeks depending on how early you book.
So that you make sure that they've got to be there.
They have got a legally binding contract that says they've got to be there.
Another important thing to have put into your contract with your videographer is an estimated completion date of when your video is going to be finished.
I know with our company, we put around six months as a completion date because we're so busy that a lot of times when we're out shooting and we don't have a lot of time to get the editing done.
But that's a good sign that we're, you know, that we're keeping busy and that we do good work.
Other things to keep in mind in your contract are to make sure they put in there how many DVDs you're going to get or if you can buy raw footage.
That's an important thing to discuss with your videographer before hand and make sure you put that in the contract, if you can buy raw footage at end.
How much he's going to charge you and also how many DVDs you're going to get and if you're allowed to make copies of that.
That should all be included in the contract so that you're not coming back later after your wedding day saying hey I need this, this and this and he's saying no you can't do that or no I won't do that.